<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Bihar Tourism</string>
    <string name="aboutbihar">Bihar is located in the eastern region of India, bordering Nepal in the North, West Bengal in the east, Uttar Pradesh in the West,Jharkhand in the South.\n The word Bihar is derived from the Sanskrit word Vihara (meaning abode). It is known as the home of Mahavir and Buddha where they have lived the most part of their life in this state. Patna is the modern capital of India.
\nBihar has a diverse climate as its temperature is subtropical by nature (hot summers and cool winters).The topography of Bihar can be easily be described as an alluvial plain drained by the Ganges River.
\nThe principal fruits are: mangoes, banana, jack fruit and litchis. \nThe wildlife majorly includes tiger, deer, bears and species of birds including the peacock, pheasant, and wild fowl.
\nHindi is by far the most common language of the state, understood by all. However regional dialects do exists in different regions. The major dialects are: Bhojpuri, Magahi and Maithili.

    </string>
    <string name="golghar">
       The Golghar is located to the west of Gandhi Maidan in Patna(Capital City).It was built by Captain John Garstin in 1786.It was built for the purpose of granary storage and it has a capacity of holding 140000 tons of grains. Its architecture resembles to those of stupa. The building has a width of 125m and a height of 29m.The structure is pillar-less with the thickness of the wall of 3.6m at the base. It has 145 steps of spiral stairway around it. The top of the Golghar gives a wonderful panoramic sight of the city.
    </string>
     <string name="district">
     Bihar has a rich cultural and heritage as it has an innumerable ancients monuments which can be dotted all over the state. Bihar has a wide number of tourist attraction place which is visited by tourist from all over the globe. \nThe state is divided into 38 districts and 101 subdivisions in Bihar State. Below are the top 5 districts where you at least must visit for tourism.
     </string>

    <string name="patnamuseum">
        Patna Museum is the state museum of Bihar. It was built in 1917 during the British Raj and is locally known as Jadu Ghar. The structure houses splendid and large collection of artifacts reflecting period of Mauryan, Gupta, Sunga, Kushan, Mughals and British era. The items on display include archaeological objects, coins, art objects, paintings, instruments, textiles, paintings, etc. It also has a collection related to Rajendra Prasad (First President of India).The structure has two floor, with each floor have dedicated galleries to display artifacts.
        </string>
    <string name="planeterium">
        Patna Planetarium (Indira Gandhi Planetarium) is one of the tourist destinations of city. It attracts a large number of visitors including both domestic as well as foreigner. It presents an educational and entertainment shows about astronomy. It also shows regular films on subjects related to Astronomy. It is situated in Indira Gandhi Science Complex and is one of the largest planetariums in India. It was conceptualized in 1989 by Chief Minister of Bihar Shri Satyendra Narain Sinha.
    </string>
<string name="patnazoo">
    Patna zoo (also known as Sanjay Gandhi Jaivik Udyan ) is located off Bailey Road, Patna. The zoo is the most frequent picnic spot of Patna. It is established in 1969 in an area of 153 acres and is one of the largest zoo in the country. It has approximately 800 animals belonging to different species and various varieties of plants and trees. It helps in maintaining an ecological balance in the surrounding areas. The zoo has an impressive collection of animals including, one-horned rhinoceros, hippopotamuses, zebras, elephants, leopards , lions, tigers including a white one, giraffes, variety of monkeys, birds, deer and many more.
</string>
    <string name="patandevi">
        Patan Devi Mandir (also known as Maa Patenshwari) is one of the oldest and the most sacred temples of Patna. It is regarded as one of the 51 siddha Shakti Pithas in India. According to Hindu Mythology, It is believed that the right thigh of the Devi Sati had fallen here while the remaining part fell to other places across the country. The temple has the black stone idols of goddess Kali, Goddess Laxmi, Goddess Saraswati and Bhairav.
    </string>
    <string name="mahavirmandir">
        Mahavir Mandir is one of the sacred Hindu Temples of Lord Hanuman located in Patna. The temple is visited by millions of pilgrims every year. The main temple has got two idols of Hanumanji one for the protection of good people and another for the elimination of the wicked persons. However the first establishment date of the temple is unknown. The reason of ever-increasing number of the devotee majorly because of the fulfillment of every wish of the devotee.
    </string>
    <string name="takhtsri">
        Takht Shri Patna Saheb is a Gurudwara(Sikh place of Worship) which was built in the remembrance of the birthplace of Guru Gobind Singh(Tenth guru of Sikh). It was built by Maharaja Ranjit Singh(the first Maharaja of Sikh Empire). Guru Gobind Singh was born in Patna and became a Guru at the age of nine years, succeeding his father Guru Tej Bahadur. He was the leader of the Sikh faith, a warrior, a poet and a philosopher.
    </string>
    <string name="buddhapark">
        Buddha Smriti Park is a park located on Frazer Road near Patna Junction. This park was developed by the Bihar Government to commemorate the 2554th birth anniversary of the Lord Buddha and was inaugurated by the 14th Dalai Lama. The central attraction of this park is the Stupa which is 200 feet high, situated in the middle of the park. The park is spread in an area of 22 acres. The park also has a meditation hall for prayers, a library and a Museum.
    </string>
    <string name="ecopark">
        Eco Park (also known as Rajdhani Vatika) is a park located in Patna. The park was inaugurated by Nitish Kumar (Chief Minister of Bihar). The park has an area over 9.18 hectares and has two lakes. The park is full of greenery with more than 3,000 varieties of plants. The park is divided into two sections; the first section has a children corner, food courts along with several fountains while the second part has theme parks along with a lake with boat rides. The both sections are interconnected through a tunnel.
    </string>
    <string name="funtasiaisland">
        Funtasia Water Park is a water park located in road on the New Bypass road, Patna and is the first water park in Bihar. The park has numerous water slides and water playgrounds. It has been developed by Takshila Seas and Resorts Private Limited, Mumbai. The Park is spread in more than 5 acres of land and it has lot of greenery as 1600 tress has been planted. The amusement park consists of nine different water rides and slides and a separate swimming pool for kids.
    </string>
    <string name="nalanda">
        Nalanda is an ancient center of higher learning in Bihar, India. Nalanda was established in the 5th century AD in Bihar. Nalanda University had eight separate compounds, 10 temples, meditation halls, classrooms, lakes and parks. The main importance of Nalanda Comes from its Buddhist roots as a center of learning. The universities attracted a large number of students across the globe. It was mainly devoted to Buddhist studies, but it also trained students in fine arts, medicine, mathematics, astronomy, etc.
    </string>
    <string name="griddhakuta">
        Griddhakuta Peak (also known as Vulture Peak) located in Rajgir, Bihar. It resembles like the shape of vulture and it is frequented by vultures in huge numbers. It is considered sacred for Buddhists as Buddha delivered some of his famous sermons here. Chairlift facilities are also available to reach the hilltop for those who find the trip physically challenging.
    </string>

    <string name="hieun">
        Hiuen Tsang Memorial is one of the major attractions and is erected in the memory of the famous Chinese traveler Hiuen Tsang. Hiuen Tsang was a compulsive traveler; he traveled extensively the whole of India. The architecture and grandeur of this hall provides a reminder of the Nalanda University. The structure houses the writings of Hiuen Tsang that provide a valuable information about the medieval India. The writings present here have also formed the base of the educational set-up of Nalanda.
    </string>
    <string name="ashokastupapeak">
      Ashok Stupa Peak is one of the tourist attractions located in Rajgir. As the name suggest it is essentially a stupa made of bricks. According to the Buddhists, the stupa was built by Ashoka as a mark of respect to Griddhakuta. There are many tourists places located nearby including , Griddhakuta Peak, Hiuen Tsang Memorial Hall, Saptaparni Cave, Rajgir Hot Springs, Bimbisar Jail, Swarna Bhandar, Ajatshatru Fort, Jarasandha ka Akhara, Sonabhandara Caves,etc.
    </string>
    <string name="sonbhandara">
        Sonbhadar (meaning gold treasure) is located in Rajgir, Nalanda District is one of the tourist attraction place. According to the Legend, these caves still hide a passage to the treasury of gold of king Bimbisara. There are two cave chambers. It is believed that one of the chambers has been the guard room with a doorway leading to king Bimbisara treasury while the second chambers has many etchings into the wall.
    </string>
    <string name="mahabodhi">
        Mahabodhi Temple is a world heritage site and is a Buddhist temple in Bodh Gaya. It marks the site where the Buddha is said to have attained enlightenment. According to the history, Prince Siddhartha Gautama attained Enlightenment at this holy place and became the Buddha. The site also contains the descendent of the Bodhi tree under which Buddha gained enlightenment. The main temple wall has an average height of 11m and its structure reflects the classical style of Indian temple architecture.
    </string>
    <string name="bodhi">
        Bodhi tree(also known as Peepal Tree) is very old sacred fig tree located in BodhGaya. According to the legend, Siddhartha Gautama is said to attain Enlightenment under this tree and later became Buddha. Bodhi tree is recognized by its heart-shaped leaves and is a frequent destination for the Buddhist pilgrims. Other Bodhi tree which have a great significance are Anandabodhi tree, Sravasti and the Bodhi tree in Anuradhapura, Sri Lanka
    </string>
    <string name="gratbuddhastatue">
        Great Buddha Statue is one of the Buddhist pilgrimage and tourist attractions site in Bodhgaya. The statue is in meditation pose (Dhyana mudra) seated on a lotus and is 25m high. It is made of a mix of sandstone and red granite. It is possibly the largest in India and is consecrated by the 14th Dalai Lama. The statue is now a symbol of holy place and enjoys constant visits of pilgrims from all over the world.
    </string>
    <string name="vishnupad">
        Vishnupad Temple is an ancient Hindu temple located along the Falgu River in Gaya. The temple is dedicated to Lord Vishnu. The temple was built with the footprints of Lord Vishnu in the center. The footprint of Lord Vishnu is 40cm long imprinted in solid rock and surrounded by a silver plated basin. The height of this temple is 30 m high and has 8 rows of beautifully carved pillars. The temple is built of large grey granite blocks.
    </string>
    <string name="ashokpillar">
        Ashoka Pillar is another tourist attraction located in Vaishali. The pillars of Ashoka are a series of column that ws built by the Mauryan King Ashoka during 3rd century BC. These pillars average between 40 to 50 feet in height and 50 tons each in weight. They are made from two different types of stone, one for the shaft and other for the capital. Each pillar is topped by an inverted lotus flower. Thus this flower along with the animal that surmounts it forms the topmost part of the column (the capital).
    </string>

    <string name="abhishek">
        Abhishek Pushkarn (also known as coronation tank) is located in Vaishali and is believed to be sacred in old days. This site has known to have where stone casket of the sacred ashes of Lord Buddha were enshrined. This site also has other tourist location like Lichchavi Stupa, etc.
    </string>
    <string name="bawan">
        Bawan Pokhar temple has got its name as it is built just next to pokhar (means pond).It is a Hindu temple but this temple is visited by the people irrespective of religion. This temple is dedicated to many Gods. The surrounding of the temple is pure and has a location for site seeing. The temple was built by the Pallava king and reflects a stone structure of the medieval period. The idols in the temple are made up of black basalt.
    </string>
    <string name="rajavishal">
        Raja Visal ka Garh represents one of the world’s first democratic republics with an elected assembly in the 6th century B.C. It is 6 ft by 10 ft high. The tower remains which are at the corner are surrounded by a moat. The platform has a circumference of one km and walls are 2 m high along with 43m wide moat, which was said to be the parliament of King Vishal. It has a capacity such that about 7000 could stand at the same time.
    </string>
    <string name="tombofshershahsuri">
        The Tomb of Sher shah suri is located in sasaram town. The tomb was basically built in the memory of Emperor Sher Shah Suri, founder of Suri Empire in northern India. His tomb shows a combination of Indo-Islamic architecture and is regarded as one of the noblest specimens of Afghan architecture in India. The structure is 122 ft high, made up of red sandstone and stands in the middle of an artificial lake and is known as Second Taj Mahal of India.
    </string>
    <string name="rohtasgarh">
        Rohtasgarh fort is located in Rohtas and is one of the most ancient forts of India. The fort is a testimony of strength and power. According to the history, the fort was built by King Harishchandra (Suryavansh Dynasty).The fort was built on a plateau at a height of 1500 ft above sea level.  There are about two thousand limestone cut steps from the foothill to the top. The structure reflects an outstanding example of Mughal architectural style.
    </string>
    <string name="maatarachandi">
    Maa Tara Chandi Temple is one of the oldest and most sacred Hindu temples and is located in the Sasaram. It is one of the 52 Shakti Peetha. The temple is dedicated to Maa Tara Chandi, which is a form of Goddess Kali. The temple has a height of 70-feet with three floors which are completely used for different temple activities. According to the Legends, the right eye of the corpse of Sati had fallen here when it was chopped off by Lord Vishnu.
    </string>
    <string name="tombofhasankhansur">
        Tomb of Hasan Khan Sur is a tourist attraction located in Sasaram. Hasan Khan Sur was father of Sher Shah Suri. The tomb was built largely with grey sandstone and was designed by the architect Aliwal Khan between 1540 and 1545. The structure is topped by an impressive dome surrounded by ornamental domed kiosks. Talking about the inside of the tomb chamber, there are 25 graves, including that of Hasan Khan Sur in the center.
    </string>


</resources>
